Now's the time to put your amazing programming skills to the test.
And this is your mini challenge.
So if you remember from our earlier lesson, we discussed a three step process we could use when developing
games, which were firstly setting up the basic structure which is importing our sprites, understanding
what the sprite should do and overall how our game should work.
Second, developing the gameplay mechanics, which is basically all our code that gives our games its
functionality, like obstacle cars moving down the road or our player car moving left or right.
Then thirdly, polishing the game.
And this is a step we are pretty much in now.
We're at the point where our game is looking great, but we just need to give it that extra touch.
And one way we can do that is by adding in music and sound effects.
So this is your challenge.
I want you to figure out a way to add a sound.
When an obstacle car passes our player car at a close distance.
So just like if you were on a road and you hear a car speeding by, it would make that sound as it passes
by.
So I want you to do the same for this game.
Two tips I will give you is that the sound you should use is called Car Vroom, and you are going to
need to use code within the sensing group.
So with that, pause the video and try to see if you can add the sound effect to your game.
Okay, well, how did that go?
Because it might not be as simple as you first thought.
Well, let's do the step.
So the first thing we're going to do is select our obstacle course sprite, as this will be the sprite
making the sound.
Then we're going to click on the sound tab and choose the sound that I mentioned.
Car.
Vroom.
Now with that added to our sprite, we can get to work.
So we want this clone to interact with our cast sprite and make it play the sound when it gets close,
so we can utilize this forever loop found in our when I start as a clone script.
Here.
What we need is to check if our clone sprite comes within a certain distance of our car sprite, so
we can move over to the sensing tab and grab this block that is called distance two.
Here we can change the input from the mouse pointer to our player car.
And then what we need is less than operators.
So we can grab one of these.
And just like you see the code here, when our Y is less than -210, our clone deletes itself.
So instead of that, we can check if the distance of our player car is less than 90, and if it is,
we can have it play the sound.
So all we need to do is grab an if conditional and then this start sound code, then stick it all together.
And finally drag this whole block inside our forever loop.
Now hitting play, as you can see.
When we pass by, I call real close.
It now makes a sound.
And yes, you'll notice that it kind of sounds like it's glitching out a bit.
And this is basically because our code keeps playing the sound continuously until our car is out of
reach.
But don't worry about that right now, as when we add in our background music, soon it'll all come
together.
Well that's it.
With that, our obstacle car has a cool sound effect, so give it a try if you didn't manage it.
Because in the next lesson, we're going to add some final touches that will complete our game.